guys this looks like a fun one it says
two quarter circles and a semicircle
what's the Shaded area and in the image
we're given that this distance is equal
to 12 and we're not really told any
information about where this is if you
want to try this on your own pause it
right now CU I'm going to solve it in 3
2 one let's pull this label down and
let's call this length right here x
since the whole thing is equal to 12
that means this piece right here is
going to be 12 - x and since this is a
quarter circle with a radius of X this
distance right here is also equal to X
next I want to focus on this side right
here it is a radius of this quarter
Circle so it's also equal to 12 - x and
then we can focus on the semicircle
let's color it red since this whole
distance is 12 - x and this piece is X
this remaining portion is going to be 12
- x - x and we can combine like terms to
give us 12 - 2x and then let's bring
this quarter Circle back now I think we
have all the measurements we need let's
split these apart actually I think we
want the radius of this semi Circle so
the radius of this thing is going to be
half of the diameter so half of 12 - 2x
is 6 - x now I think we have everything
we need let's separate these and we can
find each of these areas independently
the area of a quarter circle is < r^ 2 /
4 and the area of this quarter Circle
will also be p piun r^ 2 / 4 and then we
want to subtract this semicircle which
is p piun r^ 2/ 2 and each of these have
their own radius so let's do them
separately the radius of this quarter
circle is equal to X the r IUS of this
quarter circle is equal to 12 - x and
the radius of this semicircle is equal
to 6 - x this one's already simplified
for this one 12 - x^2 is the same thing
as 12 - x * 12 - x and then for this one
down here 6 - x^2 is the same thing as 6
- x * 6 - x and for this 12 - x * 12 - X
after you multiply it out you get 144 -
24x + x^2 and since this whole thing is
divided by 4 we can divide each of them
by 4 144 ID 4 is 36 and 24 / 4 is 6 and
then we can do the same thing down here
6 - x * 6 - x ends up being 36 - 12x +
x^2 this two down here will go to all
three of them 36 / 2 is 18 and 12 ID 2
is six and then we can take this pi and
distribute it to all three of these and
we can take this negative pi and
now we can combine like terms 36 piun -
18 piun is equal to 18 piun and this - 6
piun x and POS 6 pix will cancel each
other out now let's grab this one and
bring it down here < x^2 4 + < x^2 4 is
equal to 2 < x^2 4 and that can be
simplified into P Pi x^2 over 2 and then
we have < x^2 2 - < x^2 over 2 those
also cancel each other out so the final
answer ends up being 18 Pi let's give it
a label of units squared and put a box
around it and my favorite thing about
this problem is it does not matter what
we chose for x x could have been in any
one of these places and they will all
have the area of 18 Pi unit squar for
this one X was equal to 0 and for this
one down here x was equal to 6 and for
any of them in between they will all be
18 Pi unit squared I think that's pretty
cool how exciting